Name: DES FLAHERTY

Address: 96 The Kilns, Station Road, Portmarnock, Co.Dublin

E-Mail: desflaherty@hotmail.com

Mobile: 087-9482820

SUMMARY

Experienced data analysis professional who has worked in a variety of Industries to date including Social Media, Telecommunication, Online Mobile and Pharmaceutical. Past roles have provided exposure to various reporting tools, database programming, data management and data analysis projects. Possessing excellent presentation, communication, problem solving and analytic skills with an ability to interact with team members and stakeholders across all levels and departments from both a technical and business background.

Educational qualifications to date include a Postgraduate Diploma in Data Analytics, BSc in Multimedia Computing and a Diploma in Marketing.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Insights Analyst *LinkedIn*

October 2017 – September 2018

Employed by CPL working on site in the LinkedIn Dublin office sitting within the LinkedIn Marketing Solutions team on a contracted basis.

Responsibilities of the Role: Utilizing the LinkedIn warehouse as well as 3rd party sources of survey data to discover insights that help sales teams meet and exceed client expectations. The role involves dealing with ambiguous requests and determining which data is relevant for the brief and how to source and present the information in the most easily understood manner. Working across multiple requests simultaneously, managing expectations, and turning data into compelling stories that help LinkedIn's clients become more successful.

Technologies: Teradata, Alation, Presto, Hadoop, SQL, MS Excel, PowerPoint, Survey Data Sources.

Sales Data Analyst Vodafone Ireland

February 2015 – July 2016

Employed within the Sales Operations & Business Services (SBS) team within the Enterprise Dept. Responsibilities of the Role: Reporting on business performance to include new connections, churn, channel performance, NPS scoring & lead management. Various projects focused on data management and data quality improvement. Development of data stores using MS Access tables & UDFs. Administration and support for Salesforce CRM.

Technologies: MS Access, MS Excel, MicroStrategy, Teradata SQL, Salesforce CRM, SharePoint

CRM Data Analyst *Vodafone Ireland*

March 2014 - February 2015

Employed within the Customer Value Management (CVM) team within the Consumer Department. Responsibilities of the Role: Customer Analytics: Development of SQL reporting and deep dive analysis of customer data to identify churn trends and patterns of customer behaviour, identifying insights and communicating to business, Marketing Campaigns: Providing data leads to campaign teams for product offering and customer retention and acquisition and post campaign analysis and recommendations for campaigns.

Technologies: Teradata SQL Assistant, MS Excel, IBM SPSS Modeler

Fraud Analyst ezetop

March 2013 – September 2013

Responsibilities of the Role: Analysing day to day and historic customer data to identify fraudulent trends and patterns of behaviour. Development of custom SQL queries from the SQL Server database. Building & implementing new fraud rules into 'Accertify' Fraud Management tool based on analysis. Using insights to prevent fraud and false positive hits and increase revenue and performance. Creating weekly KPIs on Fraud Agent team performance utilising data pulled from various sources. Technologies: SOL Server Management Studio, Accertify Fraud Management system, MS Excel

Data Analyst & Web Developer *Lenovo*

December 2011 – February 2013

Responsibilities of the Role: SQL reporting on data integrity and escalating to relevant teams to ensure data standards are met. Creation of internal web tools automating manual processes to increase team productivity. UAT of new CRM software ensuring data accuracy across client portals. Liaising with BA & development teams based in China.

Technologies: SQL,PHP, MySQL, HTML, VBA, MS Excel, SAP CRM.

Campaign Analyst Eircom

April 2011 - September 2011

Responsibilities of the Role: Generating campaign leads from various sources according to marketing campaign briefs. Ensuring accurate targeted lead data was supplied to stakeholders adhering to DPC rules & regulations in a timely manner. Executing campaigns through Campaign Management System 'Chordiant Marketing Director'. Liaising with requestors on re-design of campaign briefs and data related queries.

Technologies: Teradata SQL Assistant, MS Access, BI Query, Marketing Director.

CRM Specialist *MSD Ireland (Merck)*

April 2010 - April 2011

Responsibilities of the Role: Reporting on sales team performance, drug sampling compliance tracking and product launches. Updating monthly financial sales data templates and distributing to the senior leadership team and key stakeholders within MSD Ireland -Ensuring data quality within the CRM tool and backend database. Organising & conducting 'Genesys' CRM training workshops for new Sales Reps and Managers. Helpdesk support for 'Genesys' CRM.

Technologies: SQL, Genesys CRM, MS Excel.

Commercial Administrator Staples Advantage Ireland

November 2009 - April 2010

Responsibilities of the Role: Preparation of monthly client management reporting detailing sales, order & delivery statistics and analysis. Preparing client PowerPoint presentations for account managers for client reviews. Customer data maintenance and data uploads to internal ERP system. Technologies: Progress ERP, Business Objects, MS Excel.

SAP Data Analyst Dept of Environment & Climate Change, Sydney, NSW, Australia.

October 2008 - April 2009 (Working Holiday Visa)

Responsibilities of the Role: Coordinating data collection and cleaning with regional managers and senior technical staff involved in the data migration project. Validating inventory GIS data exports sent from field staff against correct naming conventions. Converting data using Excel & MS Access queries into the required format for upload to SAP. Loading data into SAP PM test & production systems according to predetermined timelines. Technologies: SAP ERP, MS Access, MS Excel.

Clinical Programmer Quintiles Ireland Ltd

August 2007 - April 2008

Responsibilities of the Role: SAS programming and data management, Import and export of raw data files, Manipulation and transformation of raw data, Identifying and correcting data, syntax and programming logic errors. Creation of SQL listings querying the back-end Oracle database, PL/SQL Procedures, build of Clintrial application to capture drug trial data.

Technologies: Base SAS, SQLplus, Clintrial, TOAD

Database Administrator *Icon Clinical Research*

September 2006 - August 2007

Responsibilities of the Role: Development and testing of 'Oracle Clinical' data management system. Running SAS exports, validating datasets and sending direct to client companies in accordance with agreed timelines. Updating SAS scripts as directed by senior analysts.

Technologies: Base SAS, Oracle Clinical

SAP Helpdesk Analyst Allergan Pharmaceuticals

May 2006 - September 2006 (Contract)

Responsibilities of the Role: Creation of new SAP user accounts for European offices. Providing 1st level day to day application support and problem resolution for SAP issues. IT Admin: Password resets, creating IT tickets, granting access to accounts & roles.

Technologies: SAP ERP, Remedy ticketing system

SAP Master Data Administrator Abbott (Advanced Medical Optics)

July 2004 - April 2006

Responsibilities of the Role: Collection, creation and validation of customer accounts on customer master. Responsible for highlighting and solving customer master data related queries from AR & CS. Running programs to action product data loads to SAP SD, extracting reports from SAP. Technologies: SAP ERP, MS Excel

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

Postgraduate Diploma, Data Analytics, 2.1 *Dublin Institute of Technology* 2012-2014

Data Mining (SAS Miner), Statistics (SAS Enterprise Guide), Programming for Big Data (Base SAS & R), Visualization (Tableau,D3.JS), Data & Database Design (CA ERwin, Oracle Modeller, SQL Developer), Data Management (Clover ETL, Pentaho), Web Scraping (Python Beautiful Soup)

BSc (Hons) Multimedia 2.1 *Swansea Institute of Higher Education, Swansea, Wales* 2002-2004

ASP, HTML, CSS, Javascript, MS Access, Photoshop, Illustrator, Flash MX.

Graduate Diploma Multimedia Authoring & Web Development Senior College, Dun Laoghaire 2001-2002

Diploma Marketing & E-Business *Dublin Institute of Technology* 1998-2001